<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NeuBias Blog</title>
    <description>The blog of the Network of European Bio Image Analysts.</description>
    <link>https://neubias.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://neubias.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 18:05:26 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 18:05:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.6.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to NeuBIAS blog!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the very first post on our NeuBIAS blog: Welcome!!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a blog focused on image analysis build by the community for the community.
Here we can share the last updates on image analysis, including papers, tools, analysis pipelines and more! Each post will have a comment section so we can keep the community interactive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We already have a list of topics in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recent paper with interesting bioimage analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A plugin / package / add-ons that you want to share&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What I think as the problem in bioimage analyst career; career opportunities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An image analysis/processing algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Conference report&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Report about specific NEUBIAS activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just few of many topics you could write about. We need you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-have-another-communication-channel&quot;&gt;Why have another communication channel?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NEUBIAS (Network of Europian Bio Image Analysists) has already a central communication channel, that is the [Neubias official website][neubias-website].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postvak INThursday, February 22, 2018 8:05 PM
Hi Victor,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Could you prepare a list possible topics that could be written as a blog article? Proposing options is very important to motivate people. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;about a recent paper with interesting bioimage analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;my favorite plugin / package / add-ons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What I think as the problem in bioimage analyst career&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;my favorite algorithm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a conference report&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a report about specific NEUBIAS activity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save the page to your favorites and stay up to date!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are very welcome to submit your &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NeuBIAS/neubias.github.io/issues&quot;&gt;suggestions&lt;/a&gt; and please report the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NeuBIAS/neubias.github.io/issues&quot;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt; you may find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[neubias-website] : http://eubias.org/NEUBIAS/&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://neubias.github.io/news/2018/10/18/welcome-neubias.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://neubias.github.io/news/2018/10/18/welcome-neubias.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Two success training stories of NEUBIAS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/Nuno-300x225.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nuno Pimpão Martins&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instituto Gulbenkian de Ciência 
Bioimaging Unit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a trainee was a great opportunity to learn new techniques, get to know some image analysis tools and concepts and, best of all, it was a great way to meet great experienced people doing image analysis. I was able to get helpful input for some issues I had with my own data and got very good ideas on how to analyse it in a better way.
&lt;!-- more --&gt; Due to being a bit more comfortable with some of the Imagej/Fiji tools and exercises during the school, I was able to help other trainees which had less experience. This lead to further help the network and the future trainees by being a trainer in the following school for Early Career Investigators (ECI) in Oeiras, where I gave an introduction to ImageJ macros and functions. The school in Oeiras went very well and the feedback from the trainees was very good, so I was invited to co-organize the next school in Gothenburg for the ECI. Both being a trainee and a trainer have helped me immensely for my current job because I was able to learn new tools and get even more comfortable with the ones I already know, allowing me to better help my colleagues and all the users from our facility at their image analysis and on how to better analyse and answer their questions. In addition, Neubias network introduced me to a lot of interesting people with a lot of experience in imagej analysis, giving me great advice and ideas on how to better do it, which will allow me to better do my job at the facility and my future research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Anna Klemm&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/anna.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ludwig-Maximilians-University
Biomedical Center Munich
Core Facility Bioimaging&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After joining the Core Facility Bioimaging at the BMC, LMU Munich as a Bioimage Analyst, I was searching for opportunities to learn more about bioimage analysis and to network. I therefore joined as a participant in the Training School for Facility Staffs in Barcelona (TS1) and in the Training School for Bioimage Analysts in Oeiras (TS3). Both workshops were excellent. I had the opportunity to learn about image analysis workflows using a variety of software, to validate and deepen knowledge that I had before learned only on my own, and to create a network to other Bioimage Analysts. In September 2017 I was then teaching in the Early Career Investigators School in Gothenburg (TS4). The knowledge I gained – in the courses or by the interactions created in the courses – definitely helps me with my day-to-day image analysis tasks at the Core Facility. I got also a lot of material and inspirations for the local bioimage analysis courses that I am teaching. The Neubias spirit is awesome –  I recommend the Neubias courses to anyone doing Bioimage Analysis. I think they are the most efficient way to learn about new workflows and to network.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://neubias.github.io/news/2017/10/31/two-training-stories-of-nebias.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://neubias.github.io/news/2017/10/31/two-training-stories-of-nebias.html</guid>
        
        <category>neubias</category>
        
        <category>stories</category>
        
        
        <category>News</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
